<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<document><pre><code class="Python">cid = 'Website'

from pagebot.publications import Website

doc = Website(autoPages=0, title='Design Design Space')

page = doc.newPage(title='Home', name='index.html', template='home')
page.info.cssPath = 'sources/pagebot.css'

# H O M E 

box = page['Introduction']
</code></pre>

<h3>What are the dreams and dragons in your design process? How do you change a plan into a planning and mistakes into treasures? Where can you find the design space to develop?</h3>
<pre><code class="Python">box = page['Featured']['Image']
</code></pre>

<p><img alt="DesignModels2-91-1.png" src="docs/images/DesignModels2-91-1.png" /></p>
<pre><code class="Python">box = page['Featured']['Side']
</code></pre>

<h2>Repeat to improve</h2>
<p>What makes a design proces fundamentally different from a production process, is that repetition improves the result. Starting with quick sketches, ignoring most details, next steps take more time. It’s not a lineair process, it’s a iterative process, which means repeating the previous step in more detail. </p>
<pre><code class="Python">box = page['Main']['Content']
</code></pre>

<h2><em>Design Design Space</em></h2>
<h3>What is it?</h3>
<p><em>Design Design Space</em> is an online coaching environment to develop your design skills. Query your questions and improve your sketching. Acquire new techniques and research your presentations. In short, a space where you can design your design process. </p>
<p>What kind of challenges do you experience in your daily work as a designer?</p>
<p>Working closely together online with experienced designers and a group of collegue students, there is space to define your own study topics and challenges. In fact, such a selection and planning process is an integral part of the study itself. You tell us what you want, and together we’ll find a way to get there.</p>
<h3>How much time do you need?</h3>
<p>The core idea behind designing the design process, is that it doesn’t make a difference for how long you do it. A project of 1 hour, basically goes through the same stages (research – design – presentation) as a project of 1 year. Where in practice 80% of the work is done in the last 20% (or less) of the available time.</p>
<p>Of course, it matters how long you study. the stadia in the design process are fundamentally the same. Depending on the lenght of time, their will be more details to focus and to work on.</p>
<p>This mismatch – how time is spent on what – is fundamental to design. Too optimistic in the beginning (“the next one always will be better”), a design is never finished. But in the mean time, the fact that most designs are supposed to meet external requirements, the final deadline defines the quality of the result, not the opinion of the designer.</p>
<h3>1 day • 1 week • 1 month • 1 season • 1 year</h3>
<p>Study path lengths range from 1 day, 1 week, 1 month, 1 season and possibly 1 year, whatever fits best to your plans, your practical possibilities and your financial situation.</p>
<h3>What does it cost?</h3>
<ul>
<li>1 day $150</li>
<li>1 week $900 (7 days)</li>
<li>1 month $1900 (calendar month)</li>
<li>1 season $3900 (3 calendar months)</li>
<li>1 year $7900</li>
</ul>
<p>Discount or split payment for the month, season and year training can be discussed, depending on personal situation.</p>
<p>For designers who whish to extend one training level into another, a 50% discount applies to previous payed tuition.</p>
<ul>
<li>1 day followed by 1 week: 1/2 $150 + $900 = $975</li>
<li>1 week followed by 1 month: 1/2 $900 + $1900 = $2350</li>
</ul>
<h3>What is the schedule &amp; how to submit?</h3>
<p>Every 6 months, starting in March and September, a new day-week-month-season-year sequence starts, under the condition that there are at least 3 participants. </p>
<p>Day-week sequences or single day Design Games can take place on other date during the year, if the amount oof participants allows that.</p>
<p>The Design Design Space* organization mayd decide to postpone the start of a new sequence, if not enough students submitted and group them together.</p>
<p>Since working as a team of students a minimum amount of 3 is required, and also a mininum level of quality, motivation, dedication and experience. </p>
<p>Season and year-students are submitted after showing their portfolios and the result of a given assignment. They are asked to write a motivation and development plan.</p>
<p>Students finishing one training level adequately, automatically get accepted for a next level.</p>
<pre><code class="Python">box = page['Main']['Side']
</code></pre>

<p>AAA</p>
<pre><code class="Python">page = doc.newPage(title='How', name='how.html', template='home')
page.info.cssPath = 'sources/pagebot.css'
box = page['Main']['Content']

</code></pre>

<h3>How does it work?</h3>
<ul>
<li>Design students meet online with each other and the coaches in regular intervals. </li>
<li>Students get assignments for design projects with time frames ranging from several hours to several months. The assignments are challenges, for which the  specific topics can be filled by the individual students.</li>
<li>Questions how to approach these challenges, research on what skills need to be developed, what knowledge needs to be acquired and what techniques/materials need to be developed and how to design the planning for the project, are all part of the assignment. </li>
<li>With regular intervals (ranging from hours to days to once per week) the various levels of intermediate results are presented to the group of students and coaches. It is the aim of the coaches to create a safe environment in which anything can be said about any aspect of the work and the process.</li>
<li>The process of creating such a safe environment and the methods for feed-back themselves are part of the assignments, and therefor subject to sketching and modification too.</li>
<li>In the presentations feed-back is given on the presented work, but also on the presentation itself and on the process and proceedings between presentations. </li>
</ul>
<!--
## http://designdesign.space
## designdesignspace.com
-->

<p>Teachers/coaches/designers: Petr van Blokland, Claudia Mens and a crew of others</p>
<p><img alt="DSGNWK_0582BW.jpg" src="docs/images/DSGNWK_0582BW.jpg" /></p>
<h3>Design methods</h3>
<p>In magnitude of design methods have been developed, but unformtunately they all share the common goal to meet the deadline with an optimum of available functions.<br />
You may recognize that in your current design practice.</p>
<p>What most design methods don’t do is create space for designers to develop themselves. To allow unintended mistakes. Cuddle solutions that don’t seem to be porfitable right away. To spend time on acquiring skills without predefined purpose.</p>
<p>Yet, for the development of skill, such an approach is essential. </p>
<p><em>Design Design Space</em> offers that environment. To study a specific topic for a defined period of time. Offering challenges, feed back, techniques and design methods that are customized to your development.</p>
<h3>Experience</h3>
<p><em>Design Design Space</em> taps into 35 of studio projects and over 50 years of combined experience of design education. Projects ranging from corporate identities, type design, typographic software, interiors, environmental design and running Design Games.</p>
<p>Tuition needs to be payed before the training starts. <br />
No refunding is possible, but participants have the right to build in breaks for some period of time, if that is discussed before hand. </p>
<h3>What <em>Design Design Space</em> can be</h3>
<ul>
<li>A personal environment to develop design skills, by accepting design challenges, meeting with coaches and colleage students in online feed-back sessions and presentations.</li>
<li>The design of personal space (time, topic and skills) profession preparation for the rest of your life.</li>
<li>a part-time sabbatical or a virtual internship</li>
<li>a place to train design skills and tools.</li>
</ul>
<p><img alt="docs/images/HowToApplyForArtSchool.png" src="docs/images/HowToApplyForArtSchool.png" /></p>
<h3>What <em>Design Design Space</em> is not</h3>
<ul>
<li>It is not an (online) course</li>
<li>It is not an (academic) education, leading to Master or PhD</li>
<li>It is not a school</li>
<li>It is not a how to InDesign/HTML/CSS/JS/otherDesignTool training</li>
<li>It is not a series of slides, presentations or a stack of books (although these can be part of it).</li>
</ul>
<p><img alt="docs/images/DoYouReallyNeedADesigner.png" src="docs/images/DoYouReallyNeedADesigner.png" /></p>
<h3>For whom is it intended?</h3>
<ul>
<li>Graduated design students</li>
<li>Designers with experience, working in practice</li>
<li>Designers interested in improving their process</li>
<li>Designers interested in specializing a specific topic</li>
<li>Designers interested to develop skill that make them independent from future developments.</li>
<li>Designers who would like to do a follow-up refresh study, but are lacking time, finance or geographic location to make that work.</li>
</ul>
<p>In general the aim is to get graduated students as well as experienced designers back to a space of “WOW!”.</p>
<p>Focus is on design students and their individual goals. Not on predefined course content.</p>
<h3>For which designers does <em>Design Design Space</em> works best?</h3>
<ul>
<li>Open minded and willing to get valuable feed-back on their work</li>
<li>Interested to improve and change</li>
<li>Interested to participate in the work of colleague students</li>
<li>Disciplined to work hard between online sessions</li>
<li>More interested in the development of skills and challenging assignments than assessed diploma’s.</li>
</ul>
<h3>What <em>Design Design Space</em> offers</h3>
<ul>
<li>Learning how to create an environment and context to design and develop.</li>
<li>Developing the skill to design the design process.</li>
<li>Scalable traject: 1 day, 1 week, 1 month or 1 year.</li>
<li>Online (shared documents, video, hangouts).</li>
<li>Environment with experienced designer coaches and colleage students. Contact ranging from daily to weekly.</li>
<li>Each design student defines length, speed of study and select specialization topics.</li>
<li>The study finishes with a valued certificate on “graduation”, signed by external designers of statue. </li>
<li>Short term visible value for students, even with the longer time frames.</li>
</ul>
<pre><code class="Python">page = doc.newPage(title='Game', name='game.html', template='home')
page.info.cssPath = 'sources/pagebot.css'
box = page['Main']['Content']
</code></pre>

<h2>Online Design Game of 1 day</h2>
<p>For those who ever did an physical Design Game, you’ll get the same experience. Though this is an updated version, that runs online.</p>
<p>For those who never did a Design Game, this is a good way to start thinking about your design profession in a totally different way. </p>
<h3>Preparation</h3>
<p>The time frame of online Design Games, depends on the time zones of the participants. We’ll try to make that as convenient as possible, yet it could be that your starts at early dawn or late evening. <br />
Just like working for international customers would direct you to work on flexible parts of the day.</p>
<p>Virtual studios are formed from 3 or more designers. Since you are likely not in the same physical place or time zone, it is part of the game to find a way of working together. Improvisation is a form of design.<br />
As studio you may want to consider dividing tasks depending on experience and interests.</p>
<p>Design Design Space is a transparant learning environment, where the online Design Game is the most condensed example.</p>
<p>There will be several studios working in a pitch for the same assignment for the same customer. At the end of each round the design get approval points.</p>
<p>The aim is that the best performing studio after 4 rounds wins the game.</p>
<p>In each round a new assignment is given, where the formation of the studios stays the same. This way experience on what went right or wrong in the previous rounds can be used to improve the next result.</p>
<h3>Round 1: Corporate Identity</h3>
<p>The first round takes 2 hours to design and present a corporate identity. Details and requirements are given at the start of each round. </p>
<p>Studios have the possibility to present to their customer through digital media, e.g. by e-mail and hangout, asking questions, showing intermediate sketches.</p>
<p>At the end of each round, the final design of every studio is presented to their customers and the other studios. The customers will judge the process and the result and give feedback.</p>
<p>Scores of each round are visible to the group in an online document.</p>
<h3>Round 2: Another corporate Identity</h3>
<p>The second round is similar to the first round – a new corporate identity, different requirements for another customer – but in shorter time.</p>
<h3>Round 3: Magazine</h3>
<p>Design and present different types of pages of a magazine. The challenge with working in an virtual environment, is to divide the work between the designers of the studio. What visual parameters define the difference between the types of pages and which parameters make the visual coherence?</p>
<h3>Round 4: Exhibition</h3>
<p>Design and present an exhibition space, that fits the given requirements. With photos and video a physical scale model is presented to the customer and the other studios.</p>
<p>In this round all studios will judge and comment the result of all other studios. That feedback is used as part of the final score.</p>
<h3>Presentations and feedback</h3>
<p>In a presentation where are designs can be compared, a winner is selected. </p>
<h3>Conclusions</h3>
<p>Concluding the 1 day of Design Design Space, feedback is given to the studios and individual designers. What went well? What were challenges? </p>
<h4>Trained skills</h4>
<p>During the Design Game, several design skills are addressed. </p>
<ul>
<li>Organizing, time management, asking interventions</li>
<li>Management of detail levels</li>
<li>Development of sketching techniques</li>
<li>Communication between designers in a virtual studio</li>
<li>Asking the right questions to the customer</li>
<li>Selection of presentation media</li>
<li>Judging and formulating feedback to other studios</li>
</ul>
<p>Particpating in the Design Game is required for the extending studies at Design Design Space. From here students can choose to apply for one of the 1 week, 1 month, 1 season or 1 year extended programs.</p>
<pre><code class="Python">page = doc.newPage(title='Projects', name='projects.html')
page.info.cssPath = 'sources/pagebot.css'
box = page['Main']['Content']
</code></pre>

<h4>What can you do in 1 day?</h4>
<ul>
<li>Play an online Design Game, with a schedule described <a href="game.html">here</a>.</li>
</ul>
<h4>In 1 week</h4>
<p>One or more of these examples. How much can you fit in a week?</p>
<ul>
<li>Design a model exhibition space;</li>
<li>Sketch the basics of a corporate identity;</li>
<li>Design a gridded page or a scripted info-graphic</li>
<li>Draw a couple of <a href="http://typecooker.com" target="External">TypeCooker</a> words with feedback;</li>
<li>Write code for a DrawBot animation;</li>
<li>Examine how to select one of the above.</li>
</ul>
<h4>In 1 month?</h4>
<p>A selection of these examples. Or one of your own topics?</p>
<ul>
<li>Study typographic parameters;</li>
<li>Research, write, design and present a mini-thesis about a topic of your choice;</li>
<li>Design a simple corporate identity;</li>
<li>Or program the manual in PageBot;</li>
<li>Simulate a graphic design studio;</li>
<li>Design a Design Game and run it;</li>
<li>Fill a Moleskine with 100 sketch pages. Then select the best.</li>
</ul>
<h4>In 1 season?</h4>
<p>A selection of these examples. Or what would you like to do?</p>
<ul>
<li>Develop a PageBot publication;</li>
<li>Improve your sketching skills;</li>
<li>Make some RoboFont tools;</li>
<li>Design design education tools, such as games and feedback models;</li>
<li>Do almost any design project that can be done in a month.</li>
</ul>
<h4>In 1 year?</h4>
<p>A selection of these examples. Or maybe all? </p>
<ul>
<li>Become an independent typographer with noticable experience;</li>
<li>Improve your experience as type designer. Or as design educator;</li>
<li>Design Variable Font design spaces;</li>
<li>Become a designer, who knows how to write code;</li>
<li>Or how to communicatie with professional programmers;</li>
<li>You can ask a lot of relevant questions to yourself. Accepting that the answers take some more time;</li>
<li>Design deep spaces.</li>
</ul>
<h3>Specialization topics</h3>
<p>In all of the four time frames (1 day, 1 week, 1 month or 1 year) students can select a combination of specializations (where this selection process itself also is part of the design skills to be developed).<br />
The difference between the time frames is the level of details and the amount of skill training. For the rest each phase in the process is a recursive copy of one of the others.</p>
<p>The combination of any 2 or 3 topics from the list below gives each students a unique personal research environment to develop.</p>
<h4>Topics</h4>
<ul>
<li>Typography</li>
<li>Type design</li>
<li>Design for fashion</li>
<li>Design of information visualization</li>
<li>Interior and exhibition design</li>
<li>Design for multiple media from single source</li>
<li>Parametric design, programming and coding</li>
<li>Corporate identity design</li>
</ul>
<h4>Process</h4>
<ul>
<li>Design of research methods</li>
<li>Sketching techniques</li>
<li>Design the design process</li>
<li>Presentation techniques</li>
<li>Design of feedback and evaluation techniques</li>
<li>Design of testing methods</li>
</ul>
<h4>Contexts</h4>
<ul>
<li>Design education</li>
<li>Working in teams, running a studio</li>
<li>Dealing with customers</li>
<li>Design for users</li>
</ul>
<p>Each of these items contains a world of detailed knowledge and design parameters that can be developed with other students who select such a topic. As example, for typography (and with reference to adjacent topics) this next level could contain a selection of:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Typographic parameters</strong> Categories, bandwidth of possible values, presentation examples, …</li>
<li><strong>Typographic layout</strong> Principles, transformation of historic examples, whitespace, aesthetics, …</li>
<li><strong>Typographic tools</strong> Grid, type, size, leading, spacing, kerning, width, hyphenation, orientation, contrast, color, pattern, proportion, ratio, interaction, position, meaning, language, any combination and addition to the parameters of Bertin, …</li>
<li><strong>Design the process</strong> Base requirements, testing, planning, cooperation with other disciplines, research, marketing, promotion, difference between single solution and generative rules, selection and design of research methods, …</li>
<li><strong>Mathematics for designers</strong> Sin/cos/tan/atan, position, rotation, transformation matrices, column calculation, statistics, logarithmic, ranges, light game theory, principles of AI, neural networks and machine learning, …</li>
<li><strong>Type design</strong> Variation axes, design of parameters, design of selection criteria, design of the process, …</li>
<li><strong>Images as typographic elements</strong> Illustration, photography, info-graphics, ...</li>
<li><strong>Target areas</strong> Culture, fashion, politics, international relation, trade, education, …</li>
<li><strong>Educating typography</strong> Educating bachelor students, customers, users, yourself inside design cycles, presenting, writing about…</li>
<li><strong>Programming</strong> Structure, hierarchy, design of algorithms, …</li>
<li><strong>Coding</strong> All relevant languages related to typography: deepest relevant of Processing, Python, JS, PHP, CSS, HTML, XML, Objective-C, …</li>
<li><strong>Tools</strong> Deepest of Adobe applications, scripting, OSX-terminal tools, design of information conversion flows, research on raw data, …</li>
<li><strong>Device Measurements</strong> resolution, distortion, proportion, memory usage, …</li>
<li><strong>Storage techniques</strong> File, database, formats, git, JSON, plist, XML, UFO, …</li>
</ul>
<h2>Cases</h2>
<p>What we plan to do can best be describe in some cases.</p>
<h3>Case 1 Design of selection and feedback</h3>
<p>3 posters, similar and different in one series, for a topic of your choice. Assignemnt is how to judge the result and how to select from various judging methods.<br />
*How to develop criteria </p>
<h3>Case 2 Basic skills</h3>
<p>Painting of color/gray ranges. Sketching with materials, proportions, ratio and contrast.</p>
<p>Although much of your work may have digital outcome, actually making stuff opens up new directions, other points of view.</p>
<h3>Case 3 Sketching methods</h3>
<p>One week to fill a 100 page Moleskine sketchbook, design for a specific subject, context or design challenge.<br />
The presentation is showing 5 best pages in combination with validation criteria used.</p>
<h3>Case 4 Design research methods inside the design process</h3>
<p>This is the integral assignment for TypeMedia 2017 students at the end of their Master year. They have limited time of 2 weeks to write and design 3 mini-thesis document of one page each. Illustrated and documented.</p>
<h3>Case 5 Design interactive poster</h3>
<p>What is a relevant set of parameters for a poster? And how does interaction play a role in that? What is the design process? How do you test the intermediate result? What needs to happen to guearantee success?</p>
<h3>Case 6 Design of corporate identity models</h3>
<p>Research models where applications can have different usage, technique and message, and still belong to the same brand? What are parameters and what freedom do designers later in the process have?<br />
Which of these parameters need to be documented? And which can be automated?</p>
<pre><code class="Python">box = page['Footer']
</code></pre>

<p>Let us know that you think. Or if you have any questions for us. <a href="mailto:buro@petr.com">buro@petr.com</a></p>
<pre><code class="Python">page = doc.newPage(title='About', name='about.html', template='home')
page.info.cssPath = 'sources/pagebot.css'
box = page['Main']['Side']
</code></pre>

<p><img alt="docs/images/petrvanblokland.png" src="docs/images/petrvanblokland.png" /></p>
<pre><code class="Python">box = page['Main']['Content']
</code></pre>

<h3>Petr van Blokland</h3>
<p>Petr van Blokland (1956, Netherlands) graduated cum laude from the graphic arts program at the Royal Academy of Fine Arts (KABK) in The Hague in 1980.</p>
<p>With his partner Claudia Mens, Van Blokland worked for over thirty-five years as a designer in the studio they cofounded. His output ranged from sketching and model-making to programming in various languages. He specialized in systematic design: corporate identities, form systems, online publications, and tools for type design.</p>
<p>Van Blokland has taught graphic design, typography, and type design for many years at the Royal Academy of Fine Arts (KABK) in The Hague and at the Academy of Fine Arts, Arnhem. His first typeface was Proforma, a large series commissioned by Purup, a Danish manufacturer of form-preparation systems. Proforma has now been released for general use through Type Network. In 1988, Van Blokland’s work brought him ATypI’s coveted Charles Peignot Prize.</p>
<p>As cofounder and partner of Type Network, Van Blokland is a dedicated contributor and developer of new type and tools for type design. He currently teaches in the Master’s program in Graphic Design at AKV|St.Joost in Breda and at Type and Media, the postgraduate type design program at KABK in The Hague. Read more about his thoughts on design and education in this interview and in his Lubalin lecture, <a href="https://vimeo.com/133052206" target="External">Words</a> delivered at Cooper Union in 2015.</p>
<pre><code class="Python">box = page['OtherMain']['Side']
</code></pre>

<p><img alt="docs/images/claudiamens.jpg" src="docs/images/claudiamens.jpg" /></p>
<pre><code class="Python">box = page['OtherMain']['Content']
</code></pre>

<h3>Claudia Mens</h3>
<p>Claudia Mens (1957, Netherlands) graduated from the graphic arts program at the Royal Academy of Fine Arts (KABK) in The Hague in 1980.</p>
<p>With her partner Petr van Blokland, Van Blokland worked for over thirty years as a designer in the studio they cofounded. </p>
<pre><code class="Python">&quot;&quot;&quot;
Let me first introduce myself.
I'm Claudia Mens from the Netherlands.
I'm a designer I studied at the Royal Academy of Art in The Hague at the Interior Design Depart and after I graduation I studied at the post study Environmental Design for two years.
At that time, I'm speaking of medio 1980, I was the co-founder of the Design Buro
PvB + CM.
Petr and I are partners as well in business as in private. We have our work/studio in our house with three other designers through all the years and we got three sons.
This year we celebrate our 25th year aniversary of the studio.

About my work
First of all, as a designer I'm interested in people and not really in design by itself.
Before I went to the RA of A I was a school and career counselor for a couple of years.
Which is for me quit familiar with my work now; I'm designing a place for some one,
mental or physical.
I prefer my work as a designer, I love drawing, playing with design principles as color, materials, texture, type, images and so on.

In our studio it's important even it's a need to have our own projects without an inital customer.
Studying and working on something we are interested in and which we want to develop to something we don't know in advance.
This lecture is about Generous Gesture, after two years of playing in my atelier in Delft, outside our studio,  the idea of this project became something 'serious'.

Roots
After several journeys in the recent years to South America, Africa and Asia
I became very aware of my roots.
I'm raised in the south of Holland in a very romantic wooden house in a wood.
As a kid I played in our wood and in the fields around our house all day.
I could lay and hide myself under the ferns for days, for me it was a pleasant and comfortable place.

From this my idea for Generous Gesture was born.
In my atelier I made drawings inspired by my journeys. Working on this gave me a lot of joy.
And I thought of finding a way to share my drawing with others. How to make a product for some one else.Since I'm working as a designer I made various of personal gifts for friends and my family. Silk shawls with type and ornaments using in a batik technique.

Because of this experience I was thinking of a fair trade product in a batik technique,
by producing a series of shawls.
But I didn't know where to go.

At this point I have to tell you a little story of my dad;
He worked as an engineer for Philips and he was travelling for his company all over the world. 
In the 1960 he was connected with a Japanese company and he flew up and down
to Japan for ten years. And after that time, doing business with the Japanese for so long, he told us; 'From this moment, maybe a have a little bit of feeling how a Japanese might be thinking.........'
And he learned/did teach us we have to be carefull and respectfull to other cultures. As arrogant Europeans we have to try very hard to be cooperative and be humble!

So with his lesson I noticed I had to find some one who could be helpfull with my project.
as almost every good things in life, by coinsident I found Elizabeth Visser.
She is a Dutch development-aid worker and she lived and worked for years in Bangladesh with the poorest women in the rural areas of Bangladesh.
Nowadays, besides her work as a development-aid consultant she has her own business named Strawberries Fabrics, selling exclusive, traditional fabrics. All hand-made by local crafts people and women groups from different parts of the world. 
We met each other for the first time about two years ago and she was the perfect match as the important link between me and the producers, between two different cultures.
The contact between me and the people in Bangladesh passes off smoothly thanks to Elizabeth Visser.

Work in Process
Via Elizabeth I got connected with the non governemental organization Kumudini Welfare Trust in Dhaka BD. This Bengali fair trade company has an excellent reputation and is a part of the World Fair Trade Forum. The received the Award of Excellence for Handicrafts south Asia from Unesco in 2008.
Besides work, they give thousand and thousand women (25,000) also health care, workshops and they are sending their kids to school. All those women can earn a living.

My first step with this trust was to make samples in a batik technique. I sent them my first idea about a shawl and after a couple of weeks the first samples came to Delft.
They made it as precisely as possible but we saw that it was to difficult for them to draw the latin type in the batik technique. There were a lot of difficulties about the contrast of the letters they have to make. 
After a few talks we realized what their profession really is; they are the best wood carvers in the world and their Nakshi Kantha embroidery technique is appreciated worldwide. And they are very proud of making and showing this.

So after a long year of hard work, sending ideas, samples, advices to each other
whe developed a series of shawls together, which I couldn't have made without them!
The shawls changed from a square batik silk shawl with personal handwriting by the producer, to a long rectangular silk shawl, block printed and embroidered in the Nakshi Kanthi technique. In the block printing we repeated the text four times. The four different orientations make it readable from any direction.

Generous Gesture as a gift.
Every shawl has a text like Wonderful Woman, Lovely Lover, Fabulous Friend, Marvellous Mother and has an ornamentations of fern leaves as a reminiscence to our  distant past as a roof of foliage, which gave us the natural protection whe needed.

The shawl is a special gift. 
The giver shows what he or she feels to the receiver.
And a little booklet is included by the shawl, you can read that many people helped making this special gift. 
Generous Gesture is in every way a people project.
This project is so special because of the generous gestures people make to each other.
Like the craftsmen in BD by making these beautiful shawls for us.
And Kumudini Welfare trust makes the generouse gesture by providing these people work, healtcare and education. 
A Fair trade certificate is also part of the gift.
and every shawl is unique, all handmade and produced in a limited edition.

I'm very happy with the opportunity I got and I took.
Three weeks ago we received the Bronze Prize of self initiated projects in the European Desig award 2010. And of course except us, the involved people in the Netherlands, this prize is a reward for the people in Bangladesh.


The typography on this series of shawls is made by my partner Petr van Blokland.
Productus the name of this font is...... by the Fontbureau in Boston.
And the Fontbureau, by name of David Berlow, is so generous to support this project. 

FB asked me for a men scarfs on which we are working at this moment.
This scarf, made by double layed fabrics of silk and cotton, will be embroired.
The design is a combination of latin and bengoli script; Gentle Gent, also in a alliteration like the omen shawls.

Another project for Generous Gesture is in my sketchbook. I'm leaving for my atelier
within a month. 
Since a while I'm working in a nice place on Marha's Vineyard in the US where I am staying a couple of times times a year. Where a live and work as a monk, in a wooden house in a wood with ferns all over the place.
So it feels like being back on my roots.

For me this excercise of Generous Gesture is about
- my personal project
- a project of pleasure
- a project of patient
- a peoples' project

I want to finish my talk by wishing you all the best in your own work.
Make your dreams come through, what ever it is.
It's our mission to show ourselfs who we are, than the rest of the world will notice and enjoy it too.
Thank you for your attention.
&quot;&quot;&quot;
</code></pre>

<p>After three decades, running a studio from 1980 till 2010, it was time for something else. Claudia went looking and longing for the woods of her childhood. She found that feeling back on Martha's Vineyard in the USA, where she began drawing with childlike pleasure and painting. Arose leafs and fern motifs, inspired by her travels in Africa, South America and Asia.</p>
<p>She designed a series of scarves with type and motifs of leafs, produced by NGO Kumudini Welfare Trust in Bangladesh. In 2016, she started with a lot of spirit and fun <a href="peppertom.com" target="External">Pepper+Tom</a>.</p>
<p>Besides the products of Pepper+Tom, similar to work in all of the photo's on this website, design can be made by Claudia as a special custom assignment. Ask her: claudia@petr.com</p>
<h3>and others…</h3>
<p>Depending on required domain knowlegdge, other designers and professionals can be added to the team. Former students, collegue designers and lectureres and relations of the studio are available if necessary.</p></document>