<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<document><!-- PY2 -->

<pre><code>section = content.newSection()
box = section.newMain()
</code></pre>

<p><a name="PY2"/></p>
<h2>Basic coding in Python #2 <span class="wcode">(PY2)</span></h2>
<h3>Functions, methods and classes</h3>
<h4>Start November 30<span class="sup">th</span> 2020 • 2 weeks • €290</h4>
<h4>Start March 1<span class="sup">st</span> 2021 • 2 weeks • €290</h4>
<pre><code>box = box.newInfo() # No popup-arrow for running and upcoming workshops
</code></pre>

<p>After finishing <a href="#PY1">Basic coding in Python #1</a>, you have made a program that is doing one specific task. Great as that may be, it is hard to reuse that code for other projects. How nice would it be, to create a <strong>“library”</strong> with knowledge, that can be called for similar designs, without writing everything from scratch again?</p>
<p>The focus of this workshop is in making code more sustainable, using <strong>functions, methods and classes</strong>. Existing Open Source libraries are used, such as <strong>DrawBot</strong> and <strong>PageBotNano</strong>. Exercises take you step by step through the process of coding your graphic design. Instead of manually building a metaforical car, it may be more profitable to build a factory for cars. </p>
<h4>Example exercises</h4>
<ul>
<li>Make a selection of different publications and analyze the variety of (typographic) proportions that they share;</li>
<li>Sketch the relations between the extracted values and write them as coded rules;</li>
<li>Store these rules as a library of Python classes;</li>
<li>Learn to use this library in future design projects.</li>
</ul>
<p>The use of <a href="http://drawbot.com" target="external">DrawBot</a> in this workshop requires a MacOS computer.</p>
<p>Completion of workshop <a href="#TY1">Basic coding in Python #1</a> is recommended.</p>
<p><a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/1vLKGROUx03Sm3QGWEwuP1f7Uo1v4qQCmG1FlaxOT88A" target="external">Subscribe here</a></p>
<pre><code>box = section.newCropped()
#box = section.newSide() # Full visible image, not as cropped background

</code></pre>

<p><img alt="cover y=top x=center" src="images/pageBotCode.png" /></p>
<!--
<a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/1vLKGROUx03Sm3QGWEwuP1f7Uo1v4qQCmG1FlaxOT88A" target="external">
![cover y=top x=center](images/01_Instagram_FewSpaces_5.jpg)
</a>

## <a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/1vLKGROUx03Sm3QGWEwuP1f7Uo1v4qQCmG1FlaxOT88A" style="color:#F54C0A" target="external">Subscribe here</a>

--></document>