<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<document><pre><code>section = content.newSection()
box = section.newMain()
</code></pre>

<p><a name="PY3"/></p>
<h2>Coding simple scripted tools <span class="wcode">(PY3)</span></h2>
<h3>Automate repeating tasks in the design process</h3>
<h4>Start January 4<span class="sup">th</span> 2021 • 2 weeks • €290</h4>
<h4>Start March 29<span class="sup">th</span> 2021 • 2 weeks • €290</h4>
<pre><code>box = box.newInfo()
</code></pre>

<p>After finishing <a href="#PY1">Basic coding in Python #1</a> (or some other experience with Python), you are equipped with the basic coding skills to automate tasks that sometimes make a design process boring and lengthy.</p>
<p>The workshop is focused on very short scripts, only a couple of lines long, that automate repeating tasks in the design process. The result is a set of template tools that can later be used in real life projects.</p>
<p>You can start with a selection from the following exercises, but it is also possible to code your own ideas.</p>
<h4>Type related example exercises</h4>
<ul>
<li>Make a script that generates accented glyhphs</li>
<li>Check unicode-name relations</li>
<li>Make a script that checks a font for mistakes in spacing and kerning;</li>
<li>Make a script that generates TTF and OTF fonts, after doing some automated operations on the outlines.</li>
</ul>
<h4>Other example exercises</h4>
<ul>
<li>Make a script that runs through folders with images and applies Photoshop-like filters on each of them;</li>
<li>Make a script that draws graphs based on information from a spreadsheet. Save the pages in PDF documents, using your own layout;</li>
<li>Make a script that generates a simple website, based on content in a Markdown file.</li>
</ul>
<p>The use of <a href="http://drawbot.com" target="external">DrawBot</a> in this workshop requires a MacOS computer.</p>
<p>Completion of workshops <a href="#PY1">Basic coding in Python #1</a> and <a href="#PY2">Basic coding in Python #1</a> is recommended but not required.</p>
<p><a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/1vLKGROUx03Sm3QGWEwuP1f7Uo1v4qQCmG1FlaxOT88A" target="external">Subscribe here</a></p>
<pre><code>box = section.newCropped()
</code></pre>

<p><img alt="cover y=top x=center" src="images/NotesOnDesignSpaces.png" /></p></document>